<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: My Stories | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://rudylee.github.io/categories/my-stories/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rudylee.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-15T21:00:49+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://rudylee.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Science of Productivity]]></title>
    <link href="http://rudylee.github.io/2013/01/15/science-of-productivity/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-15T22:58:18+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://rudylee.github.io/2013/01/15/science-of-productivity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Continuing from my <a href="http://blog.rudylee.com/2013/01/14/my-journey-to-productivity/">previous post about productivity</a>, I just found a video that you guys might wanna check out. It covers some of the techniques from my previous post such as make your todo list doable and set up the morning dash.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My journey to productivity]]></title>
    <link href="http://rudylee.github.io/2013/01/14/my-journey-to-productivity/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-14T15:03:15+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://rudylee.github.io/2013/01/14/my-journey-to-productivity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today marks two weeks of my journey trying new method to boost my productivity. For several years, I am an avid fan of procrastination which I am still now. This has bring me a lot of troubles such as projects are off-schedule, self development postponed, and working on assignments at the last minute. I have tried several productivity techniques and sadly say, none of them show significant effect. One of the popular technique that I used is <a href="http://www.pomodorotechnique.com/">Pomodoro</a> technique. For you guys that never heard about Pomodoro, I suggest to click the link provided. For you guys that are too lazy to click the link, here is the deinition of Pomodoro that I grabbed from the website :</p>

<blockquote><p>It is a time management method created by Francesco Cirillo in the 1980s that helps you accomplish what you want to do by transforming time into a valuable ally. Why is it so popular? Because it is easy to use, and most of all, because it works!</p></blockquote>

<p>Basically the Pomodoro technique tells you to pick a task, working on it under certain time limit ( usually 25 minutes ), take a break for 5 minutes and repeat the same process again. Each cycle is what called Pomodoro, after you have finished 4 Pomodoro, you are allowed to take longer break ( 30 minutes ).</p>

<p>From my personal experience, it is a good technique but you need huge amount of self discipline. People with lack of self discipline tend to lose their focus in the middle of Pomodoro. Most of the time I am only able to do 2 perfect Pomodoro without any distractions, sometimes even less. After that usually I am end up watching Youtube, checking Facebook or even playing games.</p>

<h3>Lifehacker</h3>

<p>I am a type of person that definitely lack of self discipline. I can force and motivate myself to finish a work if there is someone watching my back, for example working in an office environment where you have colleagues monitoring what you are doing. However, one month ago I was trying find a new way to solve this problem because I am on Uni holiday and close to Christmas holiday.</p>

<p>My first choice to find solution is <a href="http://www.lifehacker.com.au/">Lifehacker</a> website. It is one of the popular websites that provides information to boost your productivity in simple ways ( sometimes ). However, because it has lot of articles, most of the time you find it hard to find article that suit your problem.</p>

<p>After trying various keywords to help me find article that match my problem, I decided to give up and looking for books instead. Luckily it&rsquo;s not that difficult because as soon as I typed &lsquo;lifehacker&rsquo; in Amazon, it comes up with this <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Lifehacker-Working-Smarter-Faster-ebook/dp/B0055AUGG8/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1357975024&amp;sr=8-2&amp;keywords=lifehacker">book</a> ( Lifehacker: The Guide to Working Smarter, Faster, and Better ). The book basically contains the same articles from the website but the good part is all the articles has been grouped into relevant chapter for easier search and read.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll suggest you skip most of the chapters in the book and only focus on the chapters that can solve your problem. In my case, I am only focus on these topics :</p>

<ol>
<li><p> Make your To-Do List Doable. Based on <a href="http://lifehacker.com/270404/how-to-make-your-to+do-list-doable">this article</a>.</p></li>
<li><p> Set Up a Morning Dash.</p></li>
<li><p> Dash through tasks with a timer.</p></li>
<li><p> Limit visits to Time-Wasting websites.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Out of those 4 topics, my favourite is number one. To-do list is a must have thing in my daily life. Not only it is useful to remind you what to do, but it also useful as a planning tool. Unfortunately, for the past few years I have done a simple mistake and made most of my to-do items in my list untouched. The mistake is simply on the way I write the todo items.</p>

<p>Before I read this article, I tend to put things such as &ldquo;Redesign personal website&rdquo;, &ldquo;Working on project A&rdquo;, and &ldquo;Working on project B&rdquo; in my todo list. According to the article, these type of tasks cannot be called tasks but projects. Tasks are more descriptive and can be done in short time. So if we pick redesign personal website project, some examples of the tasks are create the sitemap or create the home screen wire frame based on sitemap.</p>

<p>The first time I tried this approach, I am little bit sceptical. But believe it or not, I am find it easier to focus on my tasks when I write clearer task. The problem with unclear task are you will spend time to figure what to do and the chances that it will affect your motivation is higher.</p>

<p>I think that&rsquo;s all for this article, I&rsquo;ll try share my experience in the next article.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Holiday has arrived]]></title>
    <link href="http://rudylee.github.io/2011/11/23/holiday-has-arrived/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-23T18:40:11+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://rudylee.github.io/2011/11/23/holiday-has-arrived</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/3048143981_e990820985_z1.jpg"><img src="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/3048143981_e990820985_z1.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>Today is the last day of my exams and I will have holiday for 3 months. It&rsquo;s quite long considering that you spent the same amount of time for study as well. That means in one semester you will have 3 months study and another 3 months for holiday. From my perspective, it&rsquo;s not efficient, wasting time and of course wasting money :D. But who am I to judge the system, the system is there for a reason which I don&rsquo;t care much.</p>

<p>So what is my plan for holiday ? not sure, I was planning to go back to Indonesia but looks like I am gonna trapped here with a bunch of works to do. I wish I can surprise my girlfriend by I suddenly appear at her rented room and let her hug me tightly like in the movies but looks like that impossible to happen at the moment. I hope she can understand ( I know she can&rsquo;t :( ).</p>

<p>By the way, I have a number of tasks that need to be done during this break. First thing is to renew my passport which will be expired in January 2012. Without this passport, I can&rsquo;t go back to Indonesia because you need to have passport that expired more than 6 months if you are planning to go overseas. That&rsquo;s what I have been told, not sure whether it&rsquo;s true or not. It cost around 40$ to get a new passport, not too expensive considering the living cost in here is far different from Indonesia ( 40$ is just like 200k in Indonesian rupiah ).</p>

<p>The second thing is to find new place to stay that closer to my university. My current place is not bad at all considering I have lived there for almost 1 year, quite comfortable with the people that live there and it&rsquo;s just around 20-30 minutes walk from my university. But, I think it&rsquo;s better if I can find a place that nearer to my university and of course cheaper :D</p>

<p>The third one and the final one is to complete pending projects that have been waiting for months. Most of them are fun projects which I created to learn new technology. Fascinating, but the reality is not easy as it looks especially because I am well-known for being undisciplined and unmotivated person.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s all my story for this month, still need to write a blog post for last month :D</p>

<p>Picture is taken from <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/8810648@N03/3048143981/">http://www.flickr.com/photos/8810648@N03/3048143981/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short conversation with my mom]]></title>
    <link href="http://rudylee.github.io/2011/10/23/short-conversation-with-my-mom/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-23T18:54:59+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://rudylee.github.io/2011/10/23/short-conversation-with-my-mom</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sepenggal perbincangan di telepon dengan nyokap&hellip;</p>

<p>Gwa: Jadi kapan koko ted bakal married ? ( koko ted adalah panggilan gwa buat koko gwa :P )</p>

<p>Nyokap: Belom tau, rumah aja blom selesai dibangun.</p>

<p>Gwa: Oh gitu&hellip;</p>

<p>Nyokap: Jadi setelah si Teddy married, giliran lu lagi la ?</p>

<p>Gwa: Enggak donk&hellip; kan beda umur gwa ama koko 5 tahun&hellip; jadi gwa married masih 5 tahun lagi&hellip;</p>

<p>Nyokap: Emang orang tuanya Riani bolehin ? bukannya biasanya orang tua suka ketar ketir kalo belum jelas kek begini. Kalau gwa jadi orang tuanya pun khawatir.</p>

<p>Gwa: &hellip;</p>

<p>PS : kata2 sedikit diubah agar mudah dimengerti</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reasons why I hate long weekend]]></title>
    <link href="http://rudylee.github.io/2011/09/30/reasons-why-i-hate-long-weekend/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-30T17:44:44+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://rudylee.github.io/2011/09/30/reasons-why-i-hate-long-weekend</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1><strong>Too much sleep</strong></h1>

<p><a href="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/302271589_0a29afd756_z.jpg"><img src="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/302271589_0a29afd756_z.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<h1><strong>Less productive</strong></h1>

<p><a href="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/857874987_d8a2142d2a_z.jpg"><img src="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/857874987_d8a2142d2a_z.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<h1><strong>Tasks waiting after holiday</strong></h1>

<p><a href="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/6192893731_716e3567e1_z.jpg"><img src="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/6192893731_716e3567e1_z.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<h1></h1>

<h1><strong>and</strong></h1>

<h1></h1>

<h1><strong>Far away from your girlfriend</strong></h1>

<h1><a href="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/5422183699_ceda9b84c6_z.jpg"><img src="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/5422183699_ceda9b84c6_z.jpg" alt="" /></a></h1>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
