<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Unix and Linux | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://rudylee.github.io/categories/unix-and-linux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rudylee.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-15T21:00:49+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://rudylee.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My review after two months using VIM]]></title>
    <link href="http://rudylee.github.io/2013/03/30/my-review-after-two-months-using-vim/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-30T23:35:41+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://rudylee.github.io/2013/03/30/my-review-after-two-months-using-vim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On January ( Two months ago ) , I decided to learn Vim after watching screencast from <a href="http://www.destroyallsoftware.com">Destroy All Software</a>. In one of the screencast, the guy shows how fast you can program when using Vim and use plugin to make it even better.</p>

<p>I have known Vim for 4 years now but never actually keen to learn all the shortcuts. I remember I been to one of the PHP meetup in my city and one guy was presenting some of his code using Vim. One of the audience commented &ldquo;Why you need to use Vim if you have IDE and all of the GUI ?&rdquo;. At that time, I couldn&rsquo;t agree more with that guy.</p>

<p>I had always thought Vim&rsquo;s user are just trying to show off that they are different and superior. Using Vim basically separate them from GUI&rsquo;s group and put them one level above. At least, that&rsquo;s what I was thinking and apparently I am wrong.</p>

<p>After started using Vim, I can feel that I am more productive and less stressful when programming. All the shortcuts definitively help you to avoid redundancy and remove your reliance on mouse. You can navigate through the source code by only using keyboard.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Practical-Vim-Thought-Pragmatic-Programmers/dp/1934356980/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1364646960&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=vim"><img src="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/41LK8SwU4WL._SX225_-150x150.jpg" alt="Practical Vim" /></a></p>

<p>The book that I am using to learn VIM is<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Practical-Vim-Thought-Pragmatic-Programmers/dp/1934356980/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1364646960&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=vim"> &ldquo;Practical Vim : Edit Text at the Speed of Thought&rdquo; by Drew Neil</a>. If you are new with Vim, I&rsquo;ll strongly recommend to start with this book. This book has collection of tips on how to use Vim in real situation and you going to feel you learn Vim faster.</p>

<p>However, before deciding to learn Vim, you need to know that Vim is not for everyone. You know that you are not suitable for Vim when you :</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Still looking at your keyboard when typing.</p></li>
<li><p>Have problem or hate remembering shortcuts.</p></li>
<li><p>Don&rsquo;t have any curiosity to find another way to achieve something.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>If you are an IDE fan such as Eclipse, Netbeans or Visual Studio. There are some plugins that you can download to unleash the Vim power in your IDE. At the moment, I am using <a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/59ca71b3-a4a3-46ca-8fe1-0e90e3f79329">VsVim</a> to use all the Vim shortcuts when programming in C#. If you want to become better programmer, I&rsquo;ll say start using Vim and you won&rsquo;t regret it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Precise Pangolin]]></title>
    <link href="http://rudylee.github.io/2012/07/31/precise-pangolin/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-31T17:33:37+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://rudylee.github.io/2012/07/31/precise-pangolin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After spending whole day moving all my data from Ubuntu partition, I am officially running Ubuntu 12.04 64 bit. Prior to this, I was using Ubuntu 12.04 32 bit which I continuously upgrade from Ubuntu 10.04 ( it&rsquo;s been 2 years since I decided to use Ubuntu as my main operating system, time flew so fast ). It was running really slow as I have a lot of applications installed ( Rails, Django, Android SDK, Eclipse, Netbeans, etc ).</p>

<p>Basically I am happy with my new &ldquo;fresh&rdquo; installation of Ubuntu. Everything seems to run 3-4 faster than before. Booting time only takes around 20 secs from 1-2 minutes, Sublime Text fired up as soon as I clicked it and Chrome jumping smoothly like kangaroo. However, I just realize that I forgot to back up my Thunderbird email account ( damn!). Before, I set up my Thunderbird email account in POP which means that it will delete all the emails in the server. So now I am losing 17 months of emails archive which I have to explain to my boss soon.</p>

<p>So here are my applications line up for my &ldquo;fresh&rdquo; OS :
* Email Client : Thunderbird.
* IDE Text Editor : Sublime Text 2 and Vim.
* Web Server : Apache ( I was considering using Nginx, however it will take too much time rewriting all the .htaccess rule into Nginx configuration. I can&rsquo;t afford that ).
* Web Browser : Chrome.
* Source Control : Git and SVN.
* Music Player : Rhythm box ( stay with default ).
* Coming soon&hellip;</p>

<p>Next stop ? Installing Windows 7 64 bit and VirtualBox.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Assembla]]></title>
    <link href="http://rudylee.github.io/2012/04/10/assembla/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-10T15:43:50+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://rudylee.github.io/2012/04/10/assembla</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/assembla.png"><img src="http://blog.rudylee.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/assembla-150x150.png" alt="" /></a>Recently, I just canceled my <a href="http://www.github.com">Github</a> micro plan and moved all my private projects to <a href="http://www.assembla.com/">Assembla</a>. Similar to Github, Assembla also offers Git hosting and you can host private projects for free. There are several paid plans that you can choose which basically add more features such as ticketing system, wiki, FTP build, supports, etc. So if you are like me ( only need Git/SVN private hosting for your projects ), I suggest you to try Assembla.</p>

<p>Another great thing is no limitation of number of users that you can give access to your private projects. While in Github, the micro plan has limitation of one user that you can allow to access your projects.</p>

<p>There is not much I can comment about the UI as these two websites completely go in different direction. Github enhances social networking between programmers by allowing users to watch public project, fork and send pull request. This feature is very useful for open source projects to attract more contributions.</p>

<p>On the other side, Assembla does not seem to focus on public spaces. I can say that because I tried to search for PHP public project before and the search page returned &ldquo;Internal Server Error&rdquo;. Also, Assembla puts all your projects on the menu bar but only for three projects. You have to click more spaces and it will show up more projects that you have. This approach will make your life difficult if you have more than 10 projects.</p>

<p>Finally, I can say that I am happy with Assembla for the moment but I&rsquo;ll back to Github when I have bigger team and more open source projects to manage.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gource]]></title>
    <link href="http://rudylee.github.io/2011/08/28/gource/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-28T17:39:32+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://rudylee.github.io/2011/08/28/gource</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Gource is a software version control visualization tool. It was built using C/C++ ( not sure ). Several version controls that supported by Gource are Git, SVN, Mercurial and Bazaar.</p></blockquote>

<p>Basically Gource is a command line tool that you can use to visualize your project&rsquo;s progress that using software version control. Here is the example of my project :</p>

<p>Cool isn&rsquo;t it ? In my video, there is only one person because I am working for this project alone. However, if you are looking in YouTube, you can find a lot of big projects that using Gource to visualize their progress. One of the project that you should see is the Linux Kernel project.</p>

<p>Here is the link to the <a href="http://code.google.com/p/gource/">Gource Website</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apache GeoIP]]></title>
    <link href="http://rudylee.github.io/2011/04/13/apache-geoip/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-13T14:33:20+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://rudylee.github.io/2011/04/13/apache-geoip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apache GeoIP is an apache module for detecting your visitor&rsquo;s IP and block/redirect them to another website. Installing and configuring GeoIP is very easy in Ubuntu. Here are the steps :</p>

<p>1.Install the Apache GeoIP module and restart apache webserver</p>

<p><code>bash    
sudo apt-get install libapache2-geoip
sudo /etc/init.d/apache2 restart
</code></p>

<p>2.Create the .htaccess file and put in your webroot folder / website folder</p>

<p>``` apache
GeoIPEnable On</p>

<h1>Redirect one country</h1>

<p>RewriteEngine on
RewriteCond %{ENV:GEOIP_COUNTRY_CODE} ^AU$
RewriteRule ^(.*)$ <a href="http://www.canada.com$1">http://www.canada.com$1</a> [L]
```</p>

<p>In the example above, GeoIP will check whether the visitor is from Australia or not. If the visitor is from Australia then apache will redirect the visitor to <a href="http://www.canada.com.">http://www.canada.com.</a> Quite simple and straight forward. You can see another example in here<a href="http://www.maxmind.com/app/mod_geoip"> http://www.maxmind.com/app/mod_geoip</a> ( ignore the GeoIPDBFile because it will cause error ).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
